Welcome to the wonderful world of animals.
Find out what it is like to be an animal!
Their world looks, sounds and smells different!
Can you smell the air with your tongue?
Or look for food with your face?
Or see in the dark? Animals really are amazing.
They are real 'super- animals'.
Do you know which is one of the strongest animals? Almost.
It's a rhinoceros, but not this kind.
It's a rhinoceros beetle!
This beetle can lift something that is 100 times heavier than its own body weight.
Try lifting a car!
Snow leopards have very strong legs.
They can jump farther than any other animal, more than 15 metres.
That's longer than a school bus.
Some animals are really fast.
The cheetah is the fastest land animal.
It can run up to 98 kilometres per hour!
That's as fast as a car! Other animals don't hurry ever.
Like this three-toed sloth.
It's the slowest animal on earth!
It sleeps most of the day and doesn't move very much.
In the wild, it can live up to 16 years.
But can you guess which animal lives the longest?
It's the deep-sea sponge! Yes, sponges are animals, too.
Some are thousands of years old.
They can live longer than the Greenland shark, one of the world's largest carnivores.
It only lives 400 years.
Some animals are very clever: the lyrebird from Australia can copy any sound it hears.
It's better than a recording. Listen.
Do you know the sound?
Pretty amazing, don't you think?